Guide to the Stephen Prigozy telegraph collection, circa 1844-2016.
Prigozy, Stephen telegraph collection
- Series II. Telegrams
  - Western Union
    - Binder: WU Telegrams & Envelopes -- Williams et al., 1943-1975, 1983-1985 (Box 9)
    - Binder: WU Telegrams & Envelopes -- Business, 1867-1923, 1937-1952 (Box 9)
    - Binder: WU Illustrated Telegrams -- Holiday, Santagram, New Years, Thanksgiving, 1909-1936, 1947-1966 (Box 10)
      Many blanks
    - Binder: WU Illustrated Telegrams -- Easter, Valentine, Birthday, 1925-1962 (Box 10)
    - Binder: WU Illustrated Telegrams -- Mother's Day, Father's Day, Anniversary, Bon Voyage, Social Message, 1923-1936, 1949-1955 (Box 10)
    - Binder: WU Illustrated Telegrams -- World's Fair, Congrats, Wedding, Gift Order, etc., 1930-1940, 1949-1960 (Box 10)
    - WU Telegrams, 1920-1941, 1953-1954 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - WU Melody-Grams, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - WU Melody-Grams, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Telegrams and Telegraph Blanks, ca. 1860s-1870s, 1930s (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Blanks and telegrams from 1860s-1870s, illustrated telegrams, WU Money Order blanks, telegrams on authenticity research by film studios
    - Duplicate Illustrated Telegrams, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Binder: Western Union Telegrams, 1867-1954 (Box 11)
    - Western Union Telegrams to C.E. Hartung & Co., 1867-1875 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Foreign
    - Binder: Telegrams -- Europe, 1852-1953 (Box 13)
    - Binder: Telegrams -- Foreign, 1891-1966 (Box 13)
    - Binder: Telegrams -- Canada, 1853-1955 (Box 13)
      Some international, many American District Telegraph Co. at end of binder
    - German Telegrams, ca. 1920s (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - German Booklets, 1899, 1909 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      "Der Derband mittlerer Reichs=Post=und Telegraphen=Beamten", "Telegraphenwegegefek"
    - English Telegrams, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - French Telegrams, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Misc. Foreign Telegrams, 1895-1947 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      Japan, India, Australia & China, Denmark
    - Misc. Foreign Telegrams, 1864, 1883-1910s (Box 13, Folder 6)
      Germany, Argentina, others (in oversized folder)
  - General
    - Art-Grams, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Duplicate Postal Telegraph Telegrams, 1898-1942 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Duplicate Telegrams (Other), ca. 1850s-1930s (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Binder: Railroad Telegrams, 1859-1926 (Box 11)
    - Binder: Military Telegrams, 1862-1875, 1904-1944 (Box 11)
    - Binder: Postal Telegraph Business Stationary, 1886-1933, 1942-1947 (Box 12)
    - Binder: Postal Telegraph Illustrated Telegrams, 1925-1942 (Box 12)
    - Binder: Postal Telegraph Telegrams I, 1885-1914 (Box 12)
    - Binder: Postal Telegraph Telegrams II, 1891-1943 (Box 12)
    - Telegraph Covers & Messages: Collection of Stephen Prigozy (1-5), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 1-5)
      Consists of Xerox copies of the telegrams & envelopes
    - Facsimile of Letter from Mrs. Henry Ward Beecher, recommending Allcock's Porous Plasters, February 11, 1890 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Overseas Telegrams from Lawrence C. Hopkins to Julie Hall, 1942-1943 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Joseph E. Greene Co. Orders, 1910-1914 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Marconi Wireless Telegraph Company of America Shipment Forms, ca. 1910s (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Norfolk and Western Railway Co. Telegraphs, 1900-1909 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Binder: Radiograms, 1878-1963 (Box 13)
    - Binder: Telegraph Post Cards, 1898-1914, 1929-1935 (Box 14)
      Plus some unbound pages
    - Binder: Telegraph Post Cards, 1906-1911 (Box 14)
      Includes certificates for S. Prigozy from 2009 Stamp Exposition in side pockets
    - Binder: Telegraph Fakes, Fantasies, Similitudes & Spoofs, ca. 1860s-1945, 1955, 1961-2004 (Box 14)
    - Unsorted Telegrams, 1870s, 1894-1942, 1951 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Unsorted Telegrams, 1897-1898, 1909-1914 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Unsorted Telegrams, 1859-1916, 1934-1947, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Unsorted Telegrams, 1897, 1891 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Unsorted Telegrams, 1867-1884, 1906 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Blanks
      - WU Half Rate Blank, ca. 1870s (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Radiograms (Blank), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - WU Cable Grams (Blank), ca. 1900s-1920s (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - WU Cablegram Blanks, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - WU Telegrams for Air Travelers, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - WU Telefax Blanks, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - WU Blanks for Train Travel, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - Florist Telegram Blanks, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - Florist Telegram Blanks, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 18)
      - WU Day Letter Blanks, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 19)
      - Telegram Envelopes Blank, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 20)
      - WU Blanks, ca. 1870s-1910s (Box 15, Folder 21)
      - WU Blanks (General), 1910s (Box 15, Folder 22)
      - WU Blanks (General), 1920s (Box 15, Folder 23)
      - WU Blanks (General), n.d., 1920s-1930s (Box 15, Folder 24)
        One telegram from 1936 regarding stock
      - WU Blanks (General), n.d., 1910s (Box 15, Folder 25)
        One booklet with some handwritten messages from JR Bryant
      - WU Blanks (General), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 26-29)
      - Northern & Western Union Blank -- Used for Short Story, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 30)
      - WU Blanks, ca. 2009 (Box 15, Folder 31)
      - Postal Telegraph Blanks, n.d., 1930s (Box 15, Folder 32)
      - Postal Telegraph Blanks, n.d., 1920s-1930s (Box 15, Folder 33)
      - Commercial Union Telegraph Blanks, 1890s (Box 15, Folder 34)
      - Telegraph Blank in French, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 35)
      - Facsimile Blanks, n.d., 1868, 1900s (Box 15, Folder 36)
      - Postal Telegraph and Western Union (Small Blanks), 1900s-1930s, n.d (Box 19)
  - Stamps, Collect Cards, and Passes
    - Telegrams and telegraph stamps, 1873, 1905, 1932-1945 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Telegraph Stamps, 1881-1914, 1942-1947, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Including guide with some photocopies/images
    - Telegraph Stamps, 1900-1914, 1923, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Telegraph Stamps, 1878-1913, 1931-1932 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Various Companies' Stamps, 1910, 1913, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Atlantic Telegraph Co., United Wireless, WU
    - Stamps- US Companies, 1883-1900 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Northern Mutual Stamps, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Postal Telegraph Stamps, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Information about Stamps, News Clippings and Stamp Order Lists, 1989, 1993, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Stamps - Canada and an uncut sheet of American Rapid Telegram Stamps, 1890-1915, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - WU Paraphernalia (some Postal Telegraph Co. and Telepost), 1877-1962 (Box 4)
      In WU Candygram box: train passes for telegraphers, frank cards and stamp covers, clerk ID card of Henry C. Giles Jr., WU Money transfer preferred customer card of S. Prigozy, uniform buttons, WU token, business cards of H. C. Giles, matchbook with Postsl Telegraph advertisement
    - Loose Telegraph Stamps - Various Companies, 1882-1947, n.d (Box 19)
- Consumer and Publicity
  - WU Advertisements cut from newspapers, 1911-1918 (Box 4)
    Removed from non-archival binder. Name and date of publication on reverse.
  - WU Informational/Historical Publications, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - WU Promotional Labels, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Trading Cards, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - WU Rate Cards, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Messenger's Working Kits, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    Postal Telegraph kit of Walt Boldstridge and Western Union
  - "Telegraphy Successfully Learned at Home", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    Catalog for The National Automatic Telegraph Transmitter by John M. Smyth Co.
  - Sign for "Edison Light", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - WU Posters/Advertisements (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - WU Advertisements, Half Rate Cards, Receipts, Stamps, 1873, 1885-1893, 1922, 1941 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Burglar Alarm Telegraph Ad and Telephone Ads, c. 1882-1899 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Postal Telegraph Booklets and Cable Codes, c. 1894, 1925, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - The Pacific Telephone and Telegraph Co. Advertisements, 1910-1916, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Cigarette Cards, "Fleish Extract" Trading Cards, L.G. Tillotson & Co. card
  - RCA Booklets, c. 1935-1937 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - WU Consumer Booklets and Guides, ca. 1940s-1950s (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Electricity: A Modern Power, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - WU Advertisement, March 21, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - WU Booklets, c. 1949, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Includes Budget Book
  - Western Union Advertisements, News, Sign, 1938-1960, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Western Union Advertising Posters, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Nichols Electric Co. catalog (Box 18, Folder 11)
    Copy
  - Advertisements, Brochures, Rates (1), ca. 1920s-1930s, 1961, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Mostly WU, some from Postal Telegraph
  - Advertisements, Brochures, Rates (2), ca. 1920s-1940s (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Advertisements, Brochures, Rates (3), ca. 1920s-1930s (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Advertisements, Brochures, Rates (4), ca. 1920s-1930s (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Advertisements, Blanks, Business Cards, Brochures (1), ca. 1920s-1940s (Box 20, Folder 5)
    Western Union
  - Advertisements, Blanks, Business Cards, Brochures (2), ca. 1910s-1930s (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Advertisements, Blanks, Business Cards, Brochures (3), ca. 1980s (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Advertisements, Blanks, Business Cards, Brochures (4), ca. 1920s-1940s (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Notebook containing business cards and miscellaneous advertising, Undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Instrumentation and Measurement Society newsletter, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Illustrated Envelopes with Advertising of Telephone and Telegraph Companies (some with telegrams), c.1858-1974, n.d. (Box 19)
  - Postcards with Images and Advertising of Telephone and Telegraph Companies, c. 1906-1919, n.d. (Box 19)
- Machines and Memorabilia
  - Vibroplex #200690, n.d.; MU-1423 (Box 21)
  - Bunnell Receiver, early 1900s; MU-1425 (Box 21)
    Type 203, 150 ohms
  - Vibroplex Side Swipe Ke sender, early 1900s; MU-1427 (Box 21)
    #99666
  - Sender-Signal Electric Mfr. Co., ca. 1920s; MU-1422 (Box 22)
    Buzzer receiver under the hood
  - Electronic Instrument co. sender/receiver, 1950s; MU-1428 (Box 22)
    L.I.C. 1, NY, Serial #29406, "code oscillator model 706"
  - Ted Arnold Telegraph Key Stapler, n.d.; MU-1430 (Box 22)
  - WU Call Box 6-B, n.d.; MU-1434 (Box 22)
    #33393
  - Service Buzzer, 1917; MU-1436 (Box 23)
    Stromberg-Carlson Tel. Mfg. Co. Signal Co. Order #9640, includes general instructions for use
  - Jester-Cooper Co. Repeater, c. 1914; MU-1421 (Box 24)
    Sends and receives. Serial #2031
  - Receiver- no name, early 1900s; MU-1424 (Box 24)
    Shows circled N
  - WU Combination Relay (i.e. Receiver), ca. 1920; MU-1426 (Box 24)
    2 noisemakers, 2-C, 150 ohms
  - Telegraph Sounder (?), n.d.; MU-1431 (Box 24)
    "Handmade by Lewis B. Coe Crown Point IN"
  - WU Polar Relay, c. 1916; MU-1435 (Box 25)
    "WU Tel. Co. Ex 3345", "6944 Polar Relay 17-B"
  - Box of Brown Ceramic and Plastic Insulators (8 ceramic and 1 plastic), MU-1463-1471 (Box 26)
  - Box of Glass and Ceramic Insulators (11 glass, 1 white ceramic), MU-1472-1483 (Box 27)
  - Box of Glass and Ceramic Insulators (5 glass, 4 brown ceramic), MU-1484-1492 (Box 28)
  - Rubber Insulator, MU-1493 (Box 29)
  - 3 Ceramic Insulators, MU-1494-1496 (Box 29)
  - Glass Insulator (still attached to piece of the telegraph pole), MU-1497 (Box 29)
  - WU Video Services Clock, n.d.; MU-1432 (Box 29)
  - Cable Cross-Section, Spring 1966; MU-1433 (Box 29)
    "Cheshire Ground Breaking Spring 1966, American Telephone & Telegraph Company West Haven District"
  - 2 Western Union Dolly-Grams: "Just to Say" and "Happy Birthday", Undated; MU-1438-1439 (Box 30)
  - Western Union Paper Holder, Undated; MU-1440 (Box 31)
  - Western Union Coaster, Undated; MU-1441 (Box 31)
  - Western Union Ash Tray, Undated; MU-1442 (Box 31)
  - Western Union Paper Weight, Undated; MU-1443 (Box 31)
  - Western Union Ratchet Key, Undated; MU-1444 (Box 31)
  - Western Union Sign and Pins, Undated; MU-1445a-c (Box 31)
  - Western Union Blank Holder 41-B, Undated; MU-2508 (Box 31)
  - Notice about overhead telegraph wires, Undated; MU-2509 (Box 31)
  - Commercial Union Telegraph Company Printing Block for 52 cent Stamp, Undated; MU-1446 (Box 31)
  - RCA Versawatt Paper Weight, Undated; MU-1447 (Box 31)
  - WU Desk-Fax, n.d.; MU-1429
  - Pen Register, n.d.; MU-1437
    J.H. Bunnell & Co. Serial #2 602